http://www.housinginstitute.org/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy - Australasian Housing Institute
Hit enter to search or ESC to close
Cart
Member Login
About UsAbout UsGovernanceBranch CommitteesCorporate MembersCorporate Supporters & PartnersPartnership opportunitiesConstitution & RulesStrategic Plans and Annual ReportsAnnual General MeetingsContact Us
MenuToggle Navigation
MembershipYour Housing CareerDigital LearningProfessional DevelopmentProfessional CertificationMentoring ProgramCareer in HousingHousing JobsProfessional CertificationAbout
Professional CertificationContinuing Professional DevelopmentEventsUpcoming EventsCall for SpeakersEvent FeedbackAwardsAbout AwardsPast AwardsPast Awards Overview2019 Awards Winners2019 Awards Judges2017 Awards Cycle2015 Awards Cycle2013 Awards Cycle2011-2012 Awards Cycle2009-2011 Awards CycleNews & PublicationsAHI NewsHousingINFOHousingPEOPLE newsletterHousingWORKSAnnual Reports
Cart
Member Login
Search
MembershipYour Housing CareerDigital LearningProfessional DevelopmentProfessional CertificationMentoring ProgramCareer in HousingHousing JobsProfessional CertificationAbout
Professional CertificationContinuing Professional DevelopmentEventsUpcoming EventsCall for SpeakersEvent FeedbackAwardsAbout AwardsPast AwardsPast Awards Overview2019 Awards Winners2019 Awards Judges2017 Awards Cycle2015 Awards Cycle2013 Awards Cycle2011-2012 Awards Cycle2009-2011 Awards CycleNews & PublicationsAHI NewsHousingINFOHousingPEOPLE newsletterHousingWORKSAnnual Reports
About UsAbout UsGovernanceBranch CommitteesCorporate MembersCorporate Supporters & PartnersPartnership opportunitiesConstitution & RulesStrategic Plans and Annual ReportsAnnual General MeetingsContact Us
Connect
LinkedIn
Twitter
Blog
Privacy Policy
×
Login Or Join
User Login
E-mail: * Password: *
Create new account
Request new password
Our Privacy Policy
Issued 7 March 2003
Contents
A.    IntroductionB.    What kind of personal information does the Institute collect?C.    How we collect your personal informationD.    How we use your personal informationE.    Disclosure of your personal informationF.    Accuracy of your personal informationG.    Access to your personal informationH.    Security of your personal informationI.    Resolving your concernsJ.    Your consent
A. Introduction
The Australasian Housing Institute is an organisation that is, by nature, personal information-intensive. It relies on comprehensive and accurate personal information about its members and other people with whom we deal. We have robust systems and procedures in place to protect your privacy whenever we collect, store, use or disclose your personal information. If you do not wish us to disclose information about you to third parties, you must inform us and we will take immediate steps to implement your request.
Back To Top
B. What kind of personal information daes the Institute collect?
The type of information the Institute collects and holds includes (but is not limited to) personal information, including sensitive information, about:
Members' official and preferred names, titles, postnominals, personal awards, private and business address details, telephone and facsimile contact details both private and business, e-mail addresses, date of birth, gender.Members' qualifications, education and academic history, work experience and skills, occupation, employer information, insurance details, areas of practice, areas of interest, details of disciplinary action.Membership of other associations.Financial details including credit card numbers, bank account information, financial status of membership, and subscriptions to the Institute's publications.Assessment records created when a member applies for a certain membership grade. This can include Curriculum Vitaes (CVs), referees' reports etc.
Back To Top
C. How we collect your personal information
The Institute collects most personal information direct from you - for example, when you fill in an application form for membership, renewal forms etc. Information may also be collected direct from you when you deal with us personally, over the telephone, send a letter, or visit the web site. Information is also collected from you when you participate in an Institute survey. There may be occasions when a third party provides information about you, such as when you are nominated for an honour or award, or when a complaint is made against you.
Back To Top
D. How we use your personal information
The Institute will use personal information it collects for the primary purpose for which it is collected and for such other secondary purposes that are related to the primary purpose and are reasonably expected, or for which consent has been given. The Institute will use your personal information to provide you with a particular product or service and to contact you about matters pertaining to membership of the Institution.
This includes (but is not limited to) the following:
Assessing membership applications.Processing payments of applications.Making decisions relating to nomination or election to a position on the Board and/or Committees.Providing membership services such as publications, newsletters (by post or email) and other member benefits.Inviting you to partake in Institute events, seminars, professional development activities and networking activities.Contacting board and committee members to distribute agendas and minutes.We may use your personal information for purposes related or ancillary to the main reason we collect it, such as:
Internal accounting and administration.Regulatory reporting and compliance.Helping us to identify and inform you about other services that may be of benefit to you.In the event of a complaint against you we use personal information provided to us to investigate the complaint in accordance with the procedures set down in the Institute's policies and guidelines for handling complaints against members.
Back To Top
E. Disclosure of your personal information
The Institute may disclose personal information, including sensitive information, held about an individual to:
A membership committee/ board or panel to assess applications and disciplinary action.Members authorised to vote on candidates elected to office bearing positions judging committees for awards and honours.Members on the same Committee or group.The Institute may contract out some of our functions and activities. For example, we may disclose information to allow printing of renewal invoices, membership cards, and arrears notices. We may also provide names and addresses to a mailing house to mail information to you. In these situations, we prohibit the third parties from using personal information about you except for the specific purpose for which we supply it.
The Institute makes certain registers and lists publicly available. For instance, if you are recorded on a register or other listing, such as the Consultants' Register, or if you are an office bearer on the Board or committee, we disclose personal information such as name and contact details through various means, either through publications, websites or verbally to members of the public.
The Institute discloses to the public that you are a member of the Institute unless you have advised us that you do not want this information released.
The Institute treats all personal information held about you as confidential. This applies except where disclosure of your personal information is compelled by law, in the public interest, or with your consent.
In the event of a complaint, disclosure of personal information is restricted to those authorised under the Institute's policies and guidelines for handling complaints against members.
Back To Top
F. Accuracy of your personal information
If we have accurate personal information about you, it enables us to provide you with the best possible service. We take reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information is accurate, complete and up to date whenever we collect or use it. If you find that current personal information we hold about you is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date please contact us immediately. Alternatively, you may correct this yourself through the Members Only area on the Institute's website.
Back To Top
G. Access to your personal information
You may access limited personal information through our secure Members Only area on the Institute's website. Alternatively, on request, we provide you with information about you which is readily accessible and which may lawfully be provided. Your request to provide information will be dealt with in a reasonable time and we may charge you an administration fee for retrieving and sending the information to you.
Back To Top
H. Security of your personal information
The Institute protects any personal information that we hold about you from misuse and loss. We protect your privacy by restricting access to your personal information to those staff or authorised office bearers who need it, either to process information or to provide you with the services you have asked for. Our staff are responsible for handling personal information in accordance with the Privacy Act. Your personal information may be stored in hardcopy documents, as electronic data, or in the Institute's software or systems. We maintain physical security over our paper and electronic data stores and premises. We also maintain computer and network security. For example, we use firewalls (security measures for the Internet) and other security systems such as user identifiers and passwords to control access to computer systems. The Institute will keep your information for as long as it is needed to provide you with the products and services you have requested from us. We will take reasonable steps to destroy or permanently de-identify personal information when we no longer need it.
Back To Top
I. Resolving your concerns
If you believe that the privacy of your personal information has been compromised, you are entitled to complain. If you have a complaint, contact the area where you believe the breach has occurred. If your complaint is not resolved to your satisfaction, forward a written complaint to:
President,Australasian Housing Institute PO Box 6100, Mawson ACT 2607
A written complaint must include a return address, and identify the conduct that is the basis for the complaint. There are no fees for lodging a complaint.
Back To Top
J. Your consent
If you have not already done so, please tell us if you DO NOT wish the Institute to disclose:
That you are a member of the Institute.
About Professional Certification Current Certified Professionals
Useful Links
Upcoming Events Subscribe to our newsletter HousingINFO - social and affordable housing news AHI News
© 2020 Australasian Housing Institute
* Memberships outside Australia are GST exempt. NZ event registration fees are inclusive of NZ GST @ 15%
Privacy Policy
